[
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Monaco?",
        "answer": "Monaco"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which nation established dominion over South Africa in 1902?",
        "answer": "Great Britain"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the end of his term in 1963, who was Australia`s longest serving Prime Minister?",
        "answer": "Robert Menzies"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Chinese leader to use the term `Emperor` or `Huang Ti`",
        "answer": "Chin Shih Huang"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country was ruled by General Manuel Noriega until 1989?",
        "answer": "Panama"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first supreme ruler of Norway?",
        "answer": "Harald I. Fairhair -- He is portrayed by medieval Norwegian historians as the first King of Norway and reigned from c. 872 to 930."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city was the first capital of Japan?",
        "answer": "Nara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Just off the coast of Venezuela, one will find Aruba, Bonaire, and Cura\u00e7ao, collectively known as what?",
        "answer": "The three islands are collectively known as the ABC Islands, or Dutch Antilles."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Caribbean island is the closest to the United States coast?",
        "answer": "Bimini -- It is a tiny Bahamian island and is located just 50 miles east of Miami, Florida."
    },
    {
        "question": "From what did the Caribbean derive its name?",
        "answer": "Indigenous people - The word `Carib` refers to one of the Amerindian groups on the islands when they were discovered by Europeans."
    },
    {
        "question": "What city is home to the tallest skyscraper in the world?",
        "answer": "Dubai, UAE -- The Burj Khalifa soars over Dubai at a height of 2,717 ft. It has 163 floors with a hotel, residences and offices."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which American city was home to the world`s first skyscraper?",
        "answer": "Chicago -- The Home Insurance Building was 180 ft. tall. Constructed in 1885, it was demolished in 1931."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country can you find the world`s tallest twin building?",
        "answer": "Malaysia -- The Petronas Twin Towers in Kuala Lumpur are 1,483 feet tall and have a 400 ft. solid foundation, the world`s largest."
    },
    {
        "question": "What European city celebrates Christmas every year with a straw goat?",
        "answer": "G\u00e4vle, Sweden"
    },
    {
        "question": "Plymouth is the capital of what territory?",
        "answer": "Montserrat"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many countries border on the Alps?",
        "answer": "Eight"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country do the Shetland Islands belong to?",
        "answer": "United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country might you find Shabu Shabu Nabe?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first UN summit on the environment, air pollution and global warming held, in 1992?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the state of Utah?",
        "answer": "Salt Lake City"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which New England state doesn`t border the Atlantic Ocean?",
        "answer": "Vermont"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US state capital took its name from the French for `red stick`?",
        "answer": "Baton Rouge"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest island in the United Kingdom?",
        "answer": "Great Britain -- At 80,823 square miles and made up of England, Scotland, and Wales, it is the world`s ninth largest island."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European city has a hotel named after President Woodrow Wilson?",
        "answer": "Geneva, Switzerland -- Hotel President Wilson is named after him because it`s located near the United Nations Office at Geneva."
    },
    {
        "question": "In what state can visit the former home of President James Garfield?",
        "answer": "Ohio - He delivered his campaign speeches from the front porch of his home in Mentor, Ohio, which is now a National Historic Site."
    },
    {
        "question": "What doughnut-like dessert is eaten on Mardi Gras in the Midwest?",
        "answer": "Paczki -- They are typically filled with jelly or custard but are heavier than doughnuts, as they are fried longer."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Fat Tuesday known as in the U.K.?",
        "answer": "Pancake Day -- Christians fast during Lent. Pancakes were a great way to use up eggs and fat before the fast began."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the City of Bridges?",
        "answer": "Pittsburgh -- Thanks to three major rivers and their tributaries, Pittsburgh boasts 446 bridges and more than earns its nickname."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country does the food `Khachapuri` originate from?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the least visited country in the world?",
        "answer": "Nauru"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tokyo is located on which main island?",
        "answer": "Honshu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is named `Suomi` in its own language?",
        "answer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Poland?",
        "answer": "Warsaw"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Comoros?",
        "answer": "Moroni"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which territory is Australia`s capital city located?",
        "answer": "Australian Capital Territory"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state surrounds the Australian Capital Territory?",
        "answer": "New South Wales"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Australia`s Western Australia state?",
        "answer": "Perth"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is the capital of the Italian region of Tuscany?",
        "answer": "Florence"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Belarus?",
        "answer": "Minsk"
    },
    {
        "question": "Minsk is the capital of which country?",
        "answer": "Belarus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Minsk is the capital of which European country?",
        "answer": "Belarus"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which European country would you find the Tokaj wine region?",
        "answer": "Hungary"
    },
    {
        "question": "What area in the US translates from the Dutch as `Marshland`?",
        "answer": "Brooklyn"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many countries border the Black Sea?",
        "answer": "Six"
    },
    {
        "question": "As what is Formosa now known?",
        "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
        "question": "As what was Taiwan formerly known?",
        "answer": "Formosa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which river made the Grand Canyon?",
        "answer": "Colorado River"
    },
    {
        "question": "From which country did the US buy the United States Virgin Islands in 1916?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jakarta is located on which Indonesian island?",
        "answer": "Java"
    },
    {
        "question": "The northernmost point in mainland Australia is on what geographic feature?",
        "answer": "Cape York"
    }
]